<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UX-Design on Abigail Swallow</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/ux-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UX-Design on Abigail Swallow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2022-{year} Abigail Swallow. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/ux-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Horizon</title>
      <link>http://example.org/work/horizon/horizon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/work/horizon/horizon/</guid>
      <description>Designing for Inclusion and Sustainability Project Brief A product of my first-year studio course in my Master of Design Engineering program, &amp;ldquo;Horizon&amp;rdquo; was a collaborative effort among a team of three: myself, Kamila Czachorowski and Ghalya Alsanea. The project revolved around the intersection of fashion, textiles, and sustainability, aiming to re-imagine how apparel corporations approach design, particularly for gender non-conforming people.
The central ambition was to catalyze a more inclusive design approach, catering to gender-non-conforming consumers whose voices often remain marginalized in mainstream fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Apps in p5.js</title>
      <link>http://example.org/playground/weather/weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/playground/weather/weather/</guid>
      <description>Reinventing a classic As a &amp;ldquo;warmup&amp;rdquo; project for the Information Design and Visualization studio course at MIT I took in the Spring of 2023, we created weather apps. We were first tasked with creating a traditional weather app with a personal spin. I chose to create an app that helped you see the weather of your friends and family, relative to your own.
Making it &amp;ldquo;abstract&amp;rdquo; I wanted to push my design further by making an abstract interpretation of a weather app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Short History of Women&#39;s Fencing</title>
      <link>http://example.org/work/fencinghistory/fencinghistory/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/work/fencinghistory/fencinghistory/</guid>
      <description>Who is the G.O.A.T of Women&amp;rsquo;s Saber Fencing? Visualizing Fencing History (2003-2023) Project Context As a culminating project for an information design and visualization course at MIT, I transformed complex historical data from senior women&amp;rsquo;s saber fencing events into an accessible and engaging visual narrative. Ultimately creating an interactive data visualization showcasing the winners of senior women&amp;rsquo;s saber fencing events from the recognition of the sport as an Olympic event to the present day (2003-2023).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>synThread</title>
      <link>http://example.org/work/synthread/synthread/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/work/synthread/synthread/</guid>
      <description>The Process Our Vision Create a dynamic data visualization web-app merging music and textiles, transforming Spotify listening history into personalized fabric patterns.
The Challenge synThread is a dynamic data visualization web-app that seamlessly merges the realms of music and textiles. Developed as part of the Master of Design Engineering&amp;rsquo;s first-year studio course, the project was a collaborative effort among a team of three, including myself, Gail Alderson and Sophie Leamon. Our challenge was to craft an innovative data visualization concept centered around textiles, culminating in the creation of a personalized fabric design generated from a user&amp;rsquo;s Spotify listening history.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
